(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-25T23:21:53.850067",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
アイドル革命進行中！今日の主役は夢の途中
[Idol Revolution in Progress! Today's Star is on the Way to Her Dream]
世界一？可愛い
Am I the cutest in the world? (Cutest!)
宇宙一？可愛い
Am I the cutest in the universe? (Cutest!)
もっともっと聞かせて
Let me hear it more and more!
ご褒美は…目を閉じて？
Your reward is... close your eyes?
ちゅ
Chu ❤
見つけてくれてサンキュー
Thank you for finding me
愛してくれてサンキュー
Thank you for loving me
生き甲斐にしちゃってもいいのよ
You can make me your reason for living
一人じゃ無理な逆境
Adversity is too much to face alone
みんながいれば最強
But with everyone, we are the strongest
見つめ合って両想い
Staring at each other, our love is mutual
「好きになっちゃえ！」
"Just fall in love with me!"
涙じゃ何も解決しないの分かってるから
Because I know that tears won't solve anything
言葉で 行動で見せるよ
I'll show you with my words and actions.
覚悟はいい？
Are you ready?
世界一
The cutest...
可愛い
...in the whole world!
宇宙一
The cutest...
可愛い
...in the universe!
もっともっと声出して よそ見はダメ
Raise your voices more and more, don't look away!
オッケー？
Okay?
瞬きも
Even when blinking...
可愛い
...I'm cute!
存在が
My very existence...
可愛い
...is cute!
もっともっと惹きつけて ご褒美を
Attract you more and more, and as a reward...
目を閉じて
...close your eyes.
ちゅっ
Chu!
歌ってくれてサンキュー
Thank you for singing along!
笑顔くれてサンキュー
Thank you for giving me your smiles!
生きててよかったって思わ...
It makes me think "I'm glad to be alive"...
ちょっとミスる愛嬌
Making a little mistake is just my charm.
だけどやる気は最強
But my motivation is the strongest!
競い合って高め合って ベストを目指そう
Let's compete, lift each other up, and aim for the best!
苦手 ずっと逃げてちゃ愛は届かないから
If you keep running away from your weaknesses, love won't reach you.
だから何度も何度も挑もう
So let's challenge ourselves again and again!
楽しんじゃおう
Let's just have fun!
あざとくて
Being calculating...
可愛い
...is cute!
最高に
Super...
可愛い
...cute!
私だけをロックオン よそ見はダメ
Lock on only to me, don't look away!
オッケー？
Okay?
泣き虫も
Even being a crybaby...
可愛い
...is cute!
存在が
My very existence...
可愛い
...is cute!
ずっとずっと惹きつけて 輝くから
Attracting you forever and ever, because I'll shine...
約束ね
Promise me, okay?
上手に歌えてるかな
I wonder if I'm singing well...
上手に踊れてるかな
I wonder if I'm dancing well...
間違えるの怖くなるけど
I get scared of making mistakes, but...
できるできるできるできる そうだ
I can do it, I can do it, yes I can!
信じてくれる人がいる
There are people who believe in me.
この歌で君と繋がっていられる
Through this song, I can stay connected with you.
忘れられないストーリー描いていこう 行くよ！
Let's draw an unforgettable story! Here we go!
世界一
The cutest...
可愛い
...in the whole world!
宇宙一
The cutest...
可愛い
...in the universe!
もっともっと声出して よそ見はダメ
Raise your voices more and more, don't look away!
オッケー？
Okay?
瞬きも
Even when blinking...
可愛い
...I'm cute!
存在が
My very existence...
可愛い
...is cute!
もっともっと惹きつけて ご褒美を
Attract you more and more, and as a reward...
目を閉じて
...close your eyes.
ちゅっ
Chu!
現役アイドルちゅ～
[Active Idol, chu~!]
今日も鏡をチェック 最高の笑顔届ける
Checking the mirror again today, delivering the best smile.
才能に溺れないの 努力が大事よ
I won't just rely on talent, effort is what's important!
ちゃんとお勉強して ちゃんとお片付けする
Studying properly, and cleaning up properly.
だって私はそう アイドルだもん
After all, that's because I'm an idol!
好きなタイプは私 答え大好き
My favorite type is myself! I love that answer.
でも真面目一途な人 ぴったりの君だけど今はナシ
But a serious, devoted person like you is perfect... though not right now!
待たせてごめんね
I'm sorry to keep you waiting.
ファンはもっとだけど君だけのものになれないの あ、ごめん
I have so many fans, I can't belong to only you... Oh, sorry!
いつまでも好きでいて 約束よ
Please keep loving me forever. It's a promise!
ワガママなお願いね みんなのものでいたい
It's a selfish request, but I want to belong to everyone.
それでも私のこと好きですか？
Even so, do you still love me?
ピンク色のフリフリ スポットライト浴びて
Wearing pink frills, bathed in the spotlight.
いつかきっとね 君だけの私に 今はまだ歌いたい
One day, for sure, I'll be yours alone... but for now, I still want to sing!
現役アイドルちゅ〜
Active idol, chu~!
るんるんと
Skippingly,
わくわくなのよお化粧
I'm so excited to do my makeup!
コラーゲンもして
I even put on collagen,
お気に入りパックしちゃうんだ
and use my favorite face mask.
きらきらメイクは今日もバッチリよ
My sparkling makeup is perfect today too!
やっと君とデート
It's finally our date!
ちょっと話せるだけなのに なんか...
Even though we can only talk for a bit, somehow...
何度も早起きして
I woke up early so many times,
二人の時間を
because I've been looking forward
楽しみにしてるから
to our time together!
握手会 コンサート
Handshake events, concerts,
会いに来て
come see me!
君のハッピーなその顔
That happy face of yours,
ずっと覚えているわ
I'll remember it forever.
今週も来週も
I want to see you this week
会いたいな
and next week too!
オシャレなお洋服も準備して待ってるね
I'll dress up in stylish clothes and wait for you!
置いていかれても
Even if you leave me behind,
頑張る君のことは
since you're working hard,
いつまでも好きでいる
I will love you forever!
オフィシャル両想い
It's an official mutual love!
私を待ってた人にありがとう
To everyone who waited for me, thank you.
こんなにキュートな私を閉じ込めちゃうぞ
I'll keep this cute me all to myself!
クルクルレースもきらり回ってる
My spinning lace is also sparkling as it turns!
いくつになってもこのままここで輝く
No matter how old I get, I will keep shining right here!
ねえねえ 教えて？
Hey, hey, tell me,
私、今日も可愛い？
am I cute today too?
可愛いよー！
You're so cute!
いつまでも好きでいて 約束よ
Promise me you'll love me forever!
私だって君のこと
Because I...
ずっとずっと大好き
...love you forever and ever too!
一生私のこと
Will you love me
好きですか？
...for the rest of your life?
ピンク色のフリフリ スポットライト浴びて
Wearing pink frills under the spotlight,
いつかきっとね
someday I'll surely
君だけのアイドルに
become your one and only idol!
私に今をもっと歌わせて
Let me sing more of my present self!
現役アイドルちゅ～
I'm an active idol-chu~!
うわー！
Whoa!
みんな、せーのっ！
Everyone, ready, set...
こんばんわっしょーい！
Good evening-wasshoi!
どうも、ホロライブの清楚担当、みんなのアイドル、夏色...
Hello, this is Hololive's pure representative, everyone's idol, Natsuiro...
まつりでーす！
Matsuri!
ということで、今年もやってきました！
So, it has come again this year!
遅ればせながらの生誕誕生祭でございますよ！
Though a bit late, it's my birthday celebration!
まつりちゃんのね、誕生日は7月の22日
My birthday is actually July 22nd...
なんですけれども、まあ、あの、周年が6月ということでね
but since my anniversary is in June...
毎年11月にやらせていただいております
I hold it in November every year.
なので、今日も実質誕生日でございますね
So today is practically my birthday too!
はい、おめでとう、ありがとうございます！
Yes, happy birthday! Thank you so much!
そして！ 本日のハッシュタグはこちら！ ドゥルドゥルドゥン！
And! Today's hashtag is this! Drumroll!
夏色まつり誕生祭2025でございます！
It's '#NatsuiroMatsuriBirthdayFestival2025'!
いっぱいツイートしてトレンドに入れてあげてください、お願いします！
Please tweet a lot to get it trending, please!
あの、スクショとかもね、あの、撮っていただいたりとか
You can also take screenshots...
あとツイートしてくれたら、あの、まつりちゃんが後でエゴサーチさせていただきますので
and if you tweet them, I'll ego-search them later...
ぜひ、よろしくお願いしますね！ 見ちゃうよ、見ちゃうよ！
so please do! I'll be watching!
はい、そしてね、まあ、皆さんもお気づきかなと思います
Yes, and I think you all might have noticed...
本日のタイトル！ アイドル革命進行中！
today's title! 'Idol Revolution in Progress!'
今日の主役は夢の途中というタイトルにもあるように、でございますね
And as the sub-title 'Today's Protagonist is in the Middle of a Dream' suggests...
えー、本日は、アイドルさんの曲をたくさん詰め込んだ
today I've packed in many idol songs...
超とってもとっても可愛くて、ポップで、キュートで、ワクワクするようなライブになっていますので
into a super, super cute, pop, cute, and exciting live stream!
最後まで楽しんでいってくださいね！
So please enjoy it until the end!
よろしくお願いします！
I look forward to it!
コメントでもサイリウムを振ったりとか、可愛いよって言っちゃったりとか、たくさんしてくださいね！
Please wave your penlights in the chat and say 'You're cute' a lot!
ということで、この後は、皆さんお待ちかねの...
With that said, up next is the long-awaited...
ゲストパート！ やったー！
Guest Part! Yay!
はい。ちょっとね、あの
Yes. So, well...
まつりちゃん本家ダンスとかがすごく大好きなので
Matsuri-chan loves the original dances, so...
レッスンでね「お願い、やらせてください！」って言って
during lessons, I begged them, "Please let us do it!"
フォーメーションとかも含めみんなには頑張ってもらっていますので
They've worked really hard, including on the formations,
あの、君の推しがもしいたら褒めてあげてください
so if your favorite is there, please praise them!
ということで、ゲストパート準備してきますね！
And with that, I'm going to prepare for the guest part!
じゃあ、みんな「わくわく」ってコメントして待ってて
So everyone, please wait and type "wakuwaku" in the comments!
じゃあ、行ってきまーす！
Okay, off I go!
わくわく！ わくわく！ わくわく！
Wakuwaku! Wakuwaku! Wakuwaku!
サクラあっぱれーしょん
[Song: Sakura Apparation]
Hey yo, d.e.m.p.a from Akihabara to everywhere!
さあさあ 寄ってらっしゃい見てらっしゃい もう一切合切やっちゃいな
Come on, gather around, take a look! Just do absolutely everything!
ありったけの可愛いと楽しい事詰め込んで
Packed with as much cuteness and fun as possible!
さあ少年少女よ 船に乗っていざ出航じゃ
Now, boys and girls, get on the ship and let's set sail!
Hey yo, d.e.m.p.a from Japanese hot area!
みんな元気ですか？声聞かせて？
Is everyone doing well? Let me hear your voice!
はい！でんぱー！ (でんぱー！)
Yes, Dempa! (Dempa!)
ありがとさん もはや準備はバッチリのようね
Thank you! It seems you're already fully prepared!
さぁ今からでっかい船にのっていざ出航じゃ
Now, get on the giant ship and let's set sail!
さあみんなダンスダンスダンス わらじ履いてビラカンひらり
Now everyone, dance, dance, dance! Wearing straw sandals, hairpins fluttering
かっこつけてもパンツパンツパンツ はみ出てる
Even if you act cool, your pants, pants, pants are showing
めちゃくちゃのドキュメンタリー それが僕らにとってのファンタジー
A chaotic documentary, that is our fantasy
春夏秋冬感じるんだ 呼んでるんだ (あ ソレソレソレソレ)
Feeling the four seasons, calling out (Ah, sore, sore, sore, sore!)
シェイプシェイプシェイプ 胸を張っては 汗たらり
Shape, shape, shape! Standing tall, sweat dripping down
突っ走ってもこっちこっちこっち 逆方向
Even if we run headlong, it's this way, this way, this way—the opposite direction!
青春はそれでいいのだ 勘違いも味方にしちゃうのだ
That's totally fine for youth! We'll even make misunderstandings our allies!
森羅万象歌え日本踊れ日本 (あ ソレソレソレ)
All creation, sing Japan! Dance Japan! (Ah, sore, sore, sore!)
ちんとんてんしゃんとどこまでも
Chinton tenshyan, to the ends of the earth!
ほらパワフル全快で突き抜けろ
Look, break through with full-throttle power!
あっちもこっちもそっちも 祭りだわっしょい
Here, there, and everywhere, it's a festival! Wasshoi!
あっぱれあっぱれアドベンチャー
Splendid, splendid adventure!
大和の国へ摩訶不思議な言霊
To the land of Yamato, mysterious spirits of language
奇想天外さいつまでも
Always bizarre and unpredictable!
神様仏様兎様 月に祈って拝んで君思って
Gods, Buddha, Rabbits—praying to the moon, worshiping, thinking of you
半端な気持ちを断ち切って
Cutting away any half-hearted feelings
とりあえずいいか？黙ってついてこい follow me
For now, is it good? Just shut up and follow me!
君の未来を明るく照らすなんて お茶の子さいさい
Brightly illuminating your future is a piece of cake!
百花繚乱 大和撫子たちよ どでかい花火を上げましょうね
Hundreds of flowers blooming in profusion, Yamato Nadeshikos! Let's set off a giant firework!
ほら踊る阿呆に見る阿呆
Look, dancing fools and watching fools
同じ阿呆なら踊らにゃ損損損
If we're both fools, you lose out if you don't dance!
さあみんなダンスダンスダンス さらし巻いておへそちらり
Now everyone, dance, dance, dance! Wrapping sarashi chest-binders, navels peeking out
靴脱いだらソックソックソック 破れてる
If we take off our shoes, socks, socks, socks are torn
どったんばったんなこのステージ それが私にとっての正義
This chaotic, noisy stage, that is my justice!
古今東西羽ばたくんだ 聞こえるんだ (あ ソレソレソレソレ)
Flapping wings far and wide, I can hear it (Ah, sore, sore, sore, sore!)
シェイクシェイクシェイク 腕を振っては涙キラリ
Shake, shake, shake! Waving our arms, tears sparkling
強がってもきゅんきゅんきゅん 苦しいの
Even if we act tough, our hearts squeeze with painful tightness
乙女はそれでいいのだ マイナスも味方にしちゃうのだ
That's totally fine for maidens! We'll even make negatives our allies!
情意投合愛してんだ みんな大好きだだだだだだ
Mutual affinity, we love it! I love you all so much!
ちんとんてんしゃんとどこまでも
Chinton tenshyan, to the ends of the earth!
ほらパワフル全快で突き抜けろ
Look, break through with full-throttle power!
あっちもこっちもそっちも 祭りだわっしょい
Here, there, and everywhere, it's a festival! Wasshoi!
あっぱれあっぱれアドベンチャー
Splendid, splendid adventure!
でもどの国でも摩訶不思議な言霊
But in any country, mysterious spirits of language
奇想天外さいつまでも
Always bizarre and unpredictable!
神様仏様兎様 月に祈って拝んで君思って
Gods, Buddha, Rabbits—praying to the moon, worshiping, thinking of you
半端な気持ちを断ち切って
Cutting away any half-hearted feelings
とりあえずいいか？黙ってついてこい follow me
For now, is it good? Just shut up and follow me!
君の未来を明るく照らすなんて お茶の子さいさいさい
Brightly illuminating your future is a total piece of cake!
満月の下で踊りましょう
Let's dance under the full moon!
サクラ舞い散る季節と歌いましょう
Let's sing along with the season of falling cherry blossoms!
君といつかまた出逢うその日まで
Until that day we meet again someday
だから意地っ張りさんも照れ屋さん
So both stubborn ones and shy ones
八百屋さんあなたも 忘れないで
and the grocer, and you too—don't forget!
バイバイサヨウナラ
Bye-bye, goodbye!
時間たてば 事務的に やってくる
As time passes, it routinely approaches
明日なんて 我々の 明日じゃない
The tomorrow they speak of is not our tomorrow
逃げたい じゃあどこに
I want to run... but to where?
逃げれば いいのかな
Would it be okay if I ran away?
曖昧な 場所では
In such an ambiguous, uncertain place,
何にも 変われない
nothing can ever change.
立ち向かえとかやり直せよとか間違った道を
They tell us to face it, or to redo mistakes...
何度もやり直させたい あなたいったい 誰ですか？
...but who are you to force us to keep trying?
論点ずれてる人達 なんか押しのけて
Pushing aside those who miss the point...
自分の道 作らなくちゃ
...and pave our very own path!
“失敗しない”なんて契約を人は誰とも結んではいない
No one has signed a contract to "never fail".
“幸せになります”とは皆いつか昔大事な人と約束したはずだ
But we all promised a loved one "we'll be happy".
大人になるために 早く忘れることだけ覚え
Learning only to forget in order to grow up,
無理に目を背けたら 10年後の子供（きみ）を 救えないよ
if we turn away, we can't save our future selves.
全部自分が悪いと 責める君に伝えたい
To you who blames yourself, I want to say:
同じ言葉を人に 言わない君を 誰も責められない
No one can blame you for staying silent.
逃げない じゃあどこに
I won't run... but to where...
向かえば いいのかな
...should I head towards?
辛さの 根源を
If we can find the core root of this pain,
見つめ直せる場所
it can become a place where we can reflect.
いきなり 空を飛ぶ 方法なんて 知らない
I don't know how to suddenly fly into the sky.
悪と暇の 行き来は 誰ももう しないで！
No more going between evil and boredom!
“生きろ”とか 甦れ とか もういい もういい
Enough of "live" or "revive", it's enough.
逆に 逃げても いいんだよ とかいう 私は いったい 誰ですかわ？
Yet who am I to say "it's okay to run"?
分かって くれている 瞳の 輝きが
The sparkle in the eyes of those who understand...
消えてないって 証明してくれた 人たちがいる
...proves that people are still here for us.
時間たてば 事務的に やってくる
As time passes, it routinely approaches
明日なんて 我々の 明日じゃない
The tomorrow they speak of is not our tomorrow
足に 訊ねる 走れるか
I ask my feet: "Can we run?"
指に 訊ねる 開ける？
I ask my fingers: "Can we open it?"
体温に 訊ねる 血潮で 導いて いけるだろうか
I ask my body: "Will my blood lead the way?"
始まりの合図は 他の 誰にも 決めさせたくない
I won't let anyone else signal our start!
教科書の先の現代は 我々が 作っていくから
We'll shape the future beyond textbooks!
だから 逃げない
That's why I won't run away.
私は 逃げない
I will never run away.
逃げたい 君を
You, who wants to run away...
置いては ゆかない
...I will never leave you behind.
じゃなきゃ 意味ない
Otherwise, none of this makes any sense.
話したい ことない
Even if there's nothing left to say,
顔を 見なくなって
and even if we can't see each other's faces,
君を 知ってる
I still know who you are.
苦しめる 渦の中
Trapped inside this painful vortex,
頭脳の目 広げて
open the eyes of your mind...
別の角度で 見てごらん
...and try looking at it from a different angle.
そこだけ 逃げないで
Just don't run away from that very spot.
時間たてば 事務的に やってくる
As time passes, it routinely approaches
明日なんて 我々の 明日じゃない
The tomorrow they speak of is not our tomorrow
「とくベチュ、して？」
"Make it special for me?"
Oh baby 「I love you」じゃ足りない
Oh baby, "I love you" is not enough
一番大事がいい
I want to be your number one
君が作るオリジナルの
Your one-of-a-kind, original...
特別、チューして
...special kiss!
眩しくって目が覚めて
I wake up to the dazzling light
Oh yeah
愛おしく想ってよ
Hold me dear to your heart
Oh yeah
眠り姫のように 優しく口づけて
Kiss me gently, just like Sleeping Beauty
ゴミめいたこの世界
In this trashy world
Oh yeah
ピュアがかる君がいる
there you are, so pure
Oh yeah
全てに触れずに 2人だけでいよう
Let's stay together, just the two of us, untouched by everything else
私のこと 独占して 君だけのモノになってもいい
Keep me all to yourself, I don't mind becoming yours alone
なんでもある日の「なんでもない」気付いてね
Notice my "it's nothing" on any ordinary day
Oh baby 「I love you」じゃ足りない
Oh baby, "I love you" is not enough
君の「特別」にして
Make me your "special" one
ねえ もっと Give me a kiss もう私は 君でいっぱいよ
Hey, give me more kisses, I'm already so full of you
ほどけない リボン結び
An unbreakable ribbon knot
小指キュッて縛って
Tie our pinkies tight
そうよ 一生一緒がいいもん
That's right, I want us to be together forever
とくベチュが欲しい
I want your special kiss
2人きり週末は
On weekends, just the two of us...
Oh yeah
奏でてよ ハーモニー
...let's play a harmony
Oh yeah
流れ星見たら 私を想ってほしい
When you see a shooting star, I want you to think of me
あまあまな君なのに
Even though you're so sweet...
Oh yeah
広い街 吸い込まれ
...you get swallowed up by this wide city
Oh yeah
戦う姿に 大きいハナマルだね
You deserve a giant gold star for working so hard
好きなところ、優しいとこ。
The things I like: your kindness...
嫌いなとこも、優しいとこ。
...and the things I hate: also your kindness
誰にもあげない 私だけ独り占め！
I won't give you to anyone else, I'm keeping you all to myself!
う～だって 今までの人と
Because, compared to anyone before...
同じはいらないんです
...I don't want the same old thing
ねえ もっと Give me more love 私のため 生きてほしいんです
Hey, give me more love, I want you to live just for me
だから ウサギと私は
That's why rabbits and I...
さみしくさせないで
...can't bear to be lonely
そんなんじゃ束縛じゃないわ 苦しいのが好き
That's not enough to be called restraint, I like being suffocated
ショートケーキ イチゴみたいに座ってもいい？
Can I sit like a strawberry on top of a shortcake?
赤く甘い恋だもん
Our love is sweet and red
誰かにあげた 大好きも
Even the love you once gave to someone else...
返してもらって全部私に
...take it all back and give it to me
ちょーだい
Give it to me
もっと！
More!
君は神様が作る 奇跡のようなヒト
You are like a miracle created by God
拗ねた顔も その寝顔も
Your sulking face, your sleeping face...
守ってあげるね
...I will protect them all
Oh baby 「I love you」じゃ足りない
Oh baby, "I love you" is not enough
君の「特別」にして
Make me your "special" one
ねえ もっと Give me a kiss もう私は 君でいっぱいよ
Hey, give me more kisses, I'm already so full of you
ほどけない リボン結び
An unbreakable ribbon knot
小指キュッて縛って
Tie our pinkies tight
ねえ baby 最初で最後の 特別にしてね
Hey baby, make me your first and last special one
ぱぴぷぺPOP!
[Title: Papipupe POP!]
ミルクで乾杯～
Cheers with milk!
砂糖混ぜたら甘い
Add some sugar and it's sweet!
レンジでちんして温かい
Pop it in the microwave to make it warm!
レッツゴー！ぱ・ぴ・ぷ・ぺ・ぽ
Let's go! Pa-pi-pu-pe-po!
人生万歳
Hurrah for life!
この先10年安泰
We'll be safe for the next ten years!
盛れてバズったら半端な～い
If we look cute and go viral, it'll be insane!
レッツゴー！ぱ・ぴ・ぷ・ぺ・ぽ
Let's go! Pa-pi-pu-pe-po!
ポッピーハッピー
Poppy Happy!
ぴょんぴょんです ろんろんんです はっぴーです
Bouncy-bouncy, hum-hum, I'm so happy!
問題ないっす 半端ないっす これがディスコティックなバンビーナ
No problem, it's awesome, this is the discotheque Bambina
テキトーです イージーです 曖昧です ずっとこうやって
We're easy-going, carefree, and vague, let's keep doing this forever
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じで ポップに生きていこう
With a pa-pi-pu-pe-po vibe, let's live in a pop style!
ぱ・ぴ・ぷ・ぺ・ぽ
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po!
ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi!
ぱ・ぴ・ぷ・ぺ・ぽ
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po!
ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi!
毎日毎日パーリーピーポー Let me yeah! だって
Every single day, we're party people! Let me yeah, because...
横ノリ 縦ノリ 悪ノリで
Rocking left, rocking right, riding high!
映画のキャストみたいに ボンキュのボンな美ボディ 弾けて smile delight
Just like a movie cast, with a perfect hourglass body, let's burst with a smile delight!
なんでスネてんの？ うるさい！
Why are you sulking? "Shut up!"
なんで泣いてんの？ あっち行って！
Why are you crying? "Go away!"
なんで なんで
Why, why?
だって だって 女の子だもん
Because, because I'm a girl!
なんで帰っちゃうの？
Why are you leaving?
(触んないで！)
Don't touch me!
なんで怒ってんの？
Why are you mad?
あーん もう
Ah, geez!
わかってよ 言わなくても わかってよ と
Understand me, even if I don't say it, understand me...
あ、ごめん やっぱ好きー！
Ah, sorry, I love you after all!
めんどくさっ
How annoying!
きゅんきゅんです ぴょんぴょんです るんるんです きゃっきゃーです はっぴーです
I'm lovey-dovey, bouncy-bouncy, hum-humming, giggly-giggly, and happy!
問題ないっ 半端ないっ 我々ディスコティックなバンビーナ
No problem, incredible! We are discotheque bambinas!
テキトーです イージーです 曖昧です ずっとこうやって
I'm lazy, easygoing, ambiguous, let's keep doing this forever
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じで POPに生きていこう
Let's live poppingly with a "pa-pi-pu-pe-po" vibe!
ぱぴぷぺぽー！
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po!
Hi!
Hi! Hi!
ぱぴぷぺぽー！
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po!
Hi!
Hi! Hi!
ぱっと咲いて shy
Blooming suddenly, shy...
ピアニシモで kiss
A pianissimo kiss...
ブロいラップ Yo
Bro-like rap, yo!
ペプシ飲んで「あ～」
Drinking Pepsi, "Ah~"
ポップに踊ろう
Let's dance poppingly
さあ Let's Go さあ Let's Go Go
Come on, let's go! Come on, let's go, go!
Funny Funny time!
ぺっぺけぺっぺー ぺっぺけぺっぺっぺー きゅんで 3 2 1
Peppeke-peppe, peppeke-peppe-pe! Kyun in 3, 2, 1!
ぺっぺけぺっぺー ぺっぺけぺっぺっぺー おこで 3 2 1
Peppeke-peppe, peppeke-peppe-pe! Mad in 3, 2, 1!
ぺっぺけぺっぺー ぺっぺけぺっぺっぺー 笑顔で 3 2 1
Peppeke-peppe, peppeke-peppe-pe! Smile in 3, 2, 1!
ぺっぺけぺっぺー ぺっぺけぺっぺっぺー 変顔で 3 2 1
Peppeke-peppe, peppeke-peppe-pe! Funny face in 3, 2, 1!
なんかいい感じ
Feels pretty good!
(もしもーし？) なんか嬉しいね
Hello? It feels kind of happy!
(どしたん？) なんか なんか
What's up? Somehow, somehow...
やっぱ やっぱ 女の子だもん
After all, after all, I'm a girl!
なんかハッピーです
I'm kind of happy!
(うん、そんで？) なんか有頂天です
Yeah, and? I'm kind of ecstatic!
(あー もう) 幸せです
Ah, geez! I'm so happy!
聞いてー！
Listen!
へー そうなんだ
Wow, is that so?
最高です 最上です ミラクルです ウルトラです ハイパーです
It's the best! The greatest! A miracle! Ultra! Hyper!
とんでもないっ 尋常ないっ 我々アーティストなバンビーナ
Unbelievable! Extraordinary! We are artistic bambinas!
ちょっとだけ ポンクラです 爽快です ずっとこうやって
A little bit dorky, but refreshing, let's keep doing this forever
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じで POPに生きていこう
Let's live poppingly with a "pa-pi-pu-pe-po" vibe!
ぱぴぷぺぽー！
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po!
ミルクで乾杯～
Toast with milk!
砂糖混ぜたらあんまーい
It's so sweet when you mix in sugar!
レンジでチンしてあったかーい
Warm it up in the microwave!
Let's Go ぱぴぷぺぽー！
Let's go, pa-pi-pu-pe-po!
人生万歳～
Hurrah for life!
この先10年安泰
Safe and sound for the next ten years!
盛れてバズったらはんぱなーい
If we look good and go viral, it'll be insane!
Let's Go ぱぴぷぺぽー！
Let's go, pa-pi-pu-pe-po!
ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺぽー！
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po, pa-pi-pu-pe-po, pa-pi-pu-pe-po!
愛チュセヨ Lovin' you アモーレ アミーゴ
Give me love, lovin' you, amore, amigo!
ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺぽー
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po, pa-pi-pu-pe-po, pa-pi-pu-pe-po!
A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O Pー！
A-B-C-D-E-F-G-H-I-J-K-L-M-N-O-P!
People! People! Be Poppin'! Poppin'!
POP! POP! POP! POP!
最大級 最愛級 最上級 ハイスペックな人生です
Maximum, most beloved, top class, it's a high-spec life!
アイラブユー アイフォーユー だけど君がいないと寂しいな
I love you, I'm for you, but it's lonely without you...
ほんとはね やっぱりね 結局ね ずっとこうやって
Truth is, after all, in the end, let's keep doing this forever
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じで POPに生きていたい
I want to live poppingly with a "pa-pi-pu-pe-po" vibe!
ぱぴぷぺぽー！
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po!
きゅんきゅんです ぴょんぴょんです るんるんです きゃっきゃーです はっぴーです
I'm lovey-dovey, bouncy-bouncy, hum-humming, giggly-gly, and happy!
問題ないっ 半端ないっ 我々ディスコティックなバンビーナ
No problem, incredible! We are discotheque bambinas!
テキトーです イージーです 曖昧です ずっとこうやって
I'm lazy, easygoing, ambiguous, let's keep doing this forever
ぱぴぷぺぽな感じで POPに生きていこう
Let's live poppingly with a "pa-pi-pu-pe-po" vibe!
ポップにエンジョイ あれ これ どれ それ 楽しいね
Enjoy poppingly! This, that, which one? It's so fun!
ハッピーでホリック ポップにエンジョイ あれ これ どれ それ 楽しいね
Happy and holic, enjoy poppingly! This, that, which one? It's so fun!
ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺぽ Poppin' POP!
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po, pa-pi-pu-pe-po, pa-pi-pu-pe-po, pa-pi-pu-pe-po, Poppin' POP!
みんなー！ ゲストパートどうだったー？
Everyone! How did you like the guest segment?
可愛かった？ ありがとうございます！
Was it cute? Thank you so much!
ということでね、すごい続けてやってしまったんですが、
So, we performed them all in a row, but first...
まず、「サクラアパレイション」は、あずきちと、ルーナちゃんと、リリカに出てもらいました。
For "Sakura Apparition," I was joined by Azuki-chi, Luna-chan, and Ririka.
なんかすごいサクラというか、春っぽいね、ピンクな感じのメンバーをね、呼びました。
I invited members who felt very cherry blossom or spring-like, with a pink vibe.
リリカすごい頑張ってたよなぁ。すごいね、練習中も、
Ririka worked really hard, you know. Even during practice...
「あ、あ、あ、できない！」って言いながらね、頑張ってたリリカ。
...she was like, "Ah, ah, I can't do it!" but she kept pushing through.
そして、次「逃げない」ね。
And next was "Nigenai" (Don't Run Away).
「逃げない」は、ちょっと結構古めの曲なんですけど、まつりがすごい、大好きで、
"Nigenai" is a fairly old song, but I absolutely love it.
一番推していた「ゆるめるモ！」さんの楽曲で、あの、ここで歌えて、すごく嬉しかったです。ありがとうございますね。
It's by You'll Melt More!, my absolute favorite group, so I was thrilled to sing it here. Thank you!
そして、「特別して」は、もう難しかった。すごい難しかったから。
And "Tokubetsu Shite" (Make Me Special) was just so hard. It was really difficult.
だっさ、1番と2番のさ、サビの振りも違うしさ、めちゃ難しかったよ。
I mean, the choreography for the chorus was different between the first and second verses. It was crazy hard.
いや「=LOVE」さんの曲は毎回難しいけど、すごい踊ってて楽しいでございますね。
Well, songs by =LOVE are always difficult, but dancing to them is incredibly fun.
はい、そして「はぴぷぺPOP!」これ、あの、ずっと、
Yes! And then "Hapipupe POP!" For this one, since we were constantly...
こうやってやってるから、すごい疲れて、あの、汗だくになった。
...moving like this, I got so tired and absolutely drenched in sweat.
もうすごかったよ。練習中の時も、
It was intense. Even during our rehearsals...
汗だくすぎて、「ちょっと待って。ちょっと、疲れた。」とか言って、
...I was so sweaty, saying, "Wait a second, I'm exhausted."
みんなでわちゃわちゃしながらね、練習もしましたけど、すごい楽しくて、でございます。
We had a noisy, chaotic time practicing together, but it was so much fun!
そして、ちょっと紹介できてなかった、こちらのステージ！じゃーん！
And I haven't introduced it yet, but look at this stage! Ta-da!
可愛い！すっごい可愛くね、作っていただきました。
It's so cute! They made it incredibly adorable for us.
さあ、あの、アイドルソングたちばかりなので
Now, since we're only doing idol songs,
アイドルステージっていう感じにしてくださいって言ってね
I asked them to make it look like an idol stage.
こんな感じになりましたよ
And this is how it turned out!
あの、提灯もあるけどさ
There are also lanterns,
なんかすごい主張しすぎないというか、いい意味でね
but they aren't too flashy, in a good way.
あの、パステルなピンクとか
With pastel pink and other colors...
これ色変わるんですけど
These actually change colors, you know.
すごい可愛い感じにしてくれて。で、風船もね、
They made it look so cute. And the balloons too,
これ色変わるんですよ、実はね
they actually change colors as well!
ちょっとその辺も注目していただきたいなと思いますね
I'd love for you to pay attention to those details.
めちゃ可愛い。あの、後で
They are so cute. Later,
1個だけ持って帰らせてもらおうかなと思います
I think I'll take one home with me!
はい、そして
Yes, and also,
あのね、みんな気づいてなかったかなと思うんですけど
I wonder if you guys noticed,
あのね、まつりすがいるわけですよ
but there are Matsurisus here!
そう、周年、1周年の周年ライブのときにはいなかったんですよ
Yes, they weren't here during the anniversary live!
ね、エビフライオンがいたの、代わりに
Ebi Fryon was here instead.
他のさ、はーとんとかはさ
While other fan mascots like Haatons
ちゃんと、はーとんとしていたのに、リスナーさんの姿でいたのに
were there representing their listeners,
まつりだけね、まつりすが居なくてエビフライオンだったんで
only Matsurisu wasn't here, replaced by Ebi Fryon.
今回、良かったね、これって
So I'm glad they are here this time!
ということで、早速、続いての曲いきましょうか
With that said, let's move on to the next song!
続いての曲もアイドルソングでございますよ
The next song is also an idol song!
それでは聴いてください。アイドルソング。
Please listen to: IDOL SONG.
ねぇ アイドルになりたい
Hey, I want to be an idol.
すっごい愛をあげたい
I want to give you so much love.
この命の使い方を君に愛されたい
I want you to love the way I use this life of mine.
はーい！
Okay!
えくぼは恋の落とし穴 夢中にさせちゃうぞ
Dimples are a love trap, I'll make you fall crazy for me!
埼玉県から来ました フレッシュレモンになりたいのー
I came from Saitama, I want to be a fresh lemon~
ファンの方が恋人です
Fans are my lovers!
真面目なアイドル 真面目にアイドル
Serious idol, seriously an idol,
年中無休24時間 ずっと笑顔でうさちゃんピース
Open 24/7, year-round, always smiling with bunny peace!
はーい！
Okay!
あなたの心にホールインワン
A hole-in-one in your heart!
あなたのハートにアクセスします
Accessing your heart!
みんなのドキドキにシュートします
Shooting into everyone's pounding hearts!
なんでもいいからレスください
Give me some feedback, anything is fine!
ハゲ気味のみなさーーん？
Are you guys starting to go bald...?
ぬおおおおお
Nuuuoooooh!
よし、今日もかわいい
Alright, cute today as well!
こゆビーム！
Little finger beam!
ねぇ アイドルになりたい
Hey, I want to be an idol.
ずっとはわからないけど
I don't know if it'll be forever, but
幸せに似てるシャンプーの香りを見つけたの
I found a shampoo scent that smells like happiness.
歌で人の気持ち
So I can brighten
明るくできるように
people's feelings with songs,
きっと人生にくじけている人がいると思うから
because I'm sure there are discouraged people out there.
はーい 好きでいいよ
Yes, it's okay to love me!
はーい もっと簡単に
Yes, more easily!
はーい 好きでいいよ
Yes, it's okay to love me!
はーい もっと叫べ
Yes, shout louder!
はーい 好きでいいよ
Yes, it's okay to love me!
はーい もっと簡単に
Yes, more easily!
はーい 好きでいいよ
Yes, it's okay to love me!
はーい もっと叫べ
Yes, shout louder!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
はーい！
Okay!
めちゃくちゃ話すのが苦手 可愛い自分気持ち悪い
I'm terrible at talking, cute me is disgusting!
世界のルールを歌って踊って破壊する
Sing, dance, and destroy the rules of the world!
燃える闘魂、燃える髪の毛
Burning fighting spirit, burning hair!
見た目は純白、中身は真っ黒
Looks pure white, inside is pitch black!
ちょっぴりおバカな小さな巨人
A slightly silly little giant!
感電少女
Electrified girl!
みるくとみゆきを混ぜるだけ あっという間に...みるきー
Just mix milk and Miyuki, and in no time... Milky!
ちちんぷいぷい 魔法にかーかれ あっかかっちゃったー
Chichinpui-pui, be cast under a spell! Ah, you are!
トイレなんて行ったことないよ ピンクのマシュマロが出まーす
I never go to the restroom! Pink marshmallows come out!
3時のおやつはマカロンが良き ふわふわガール目指しちゅう
For 3 PM snack, macarons are best! Aiming to be fluffy!
ねぇ アイドルがたのしい
Hey, being an idol is fun.
いっぱい愛が舞ってる
A lot of love is dancing in the air.
ステージから見る景色がずっと宝物さ
The view from the stage will always be a treasure.
ねぇ もし君が他界したとしても 君が
Hey, even if you leave the fandom,
必要な分の幸せは あげられていたかな
I wonder if I was able to give you enough happiness.
はーい 好きでいいよ
Yes, it's okay to love me!
はーい もっと大胆に
Yes, more boldly!
はーい 好きでいいよ
Yes, it's okay to love me!
はーい もっと叫べ
Yes, shout louder!
はーい 好きでいいよ
Yes, it's okay to love me!
はーい もっと大胆に
Yes, more boldly!
はーい 好きでいいよ
Yes, it's okay to love me!
はーい もっと叫べ
Yes, shout louder!
フーー！！！
Fu!!!
はーい！
Okay!
360度どこから見ても アイドル 出席番号ラッキー7
An idol from any angle, 360 degrees! Attendance Lucky 7!
好きになってもいいですかー？
Is it okay if you fall in love with me?
僕のいもうとがこんなに可愛いわけがない 担当
In charge of "My Little Sister Can't Be This Cute"!
ぷにっぷにー？ ぴちっぴちでしょ
Squishy-squishy? No, fresh and youthful!
こんにちはネギネギー
Hello, Negi-Negi!
推せる愛せるランドセル
Lovable Randoseru!
今日も明日も明後日も キラキラパワー全開
Today, tomorrow, and the day after, full sparkle power!
がんばって生田
Do your best, Ikuta!
みーんなの目線をいただき〜まゆゆ
I'll take everyone's gaze... Mayuyu!
泣き虫で甘えん坊なみんなの妹
A crybaby and spoiled child, everyone's little sister!
ねぇ アイドルがたのしい
Hey, being an idol is fun.
いっぱい愛が舞ってる
A lot of love is dancing in the air.
ステージから見る景色が...
The view from the stage...
全部トモダチのものさ
They all belong to friends.
ねえ アイドルになりたい
Hey, I want to be an idol!
すごい愛をあげたい
I want to give you amazing love!
この命の使い方を 君に愛されて決定！
How I use my life is decided by being loved by you!
好きでいいよ もっと簡単に
It's okay to love me! Keep it simpler!
好きでいいよ もっと叫んで
It's okay to love me! Scream it louder!
好きでいいよ もっと簡単に
It's okay to love me! Keep it simpler!
好きでいいよ もっと叫んで
It's okay to love me! Scream it louder!
好きでいいよ もっと大胆に
It's okay to love me! Be more daring!
好きでいいよ もっと叫んで
It's okay to love me! Scream it louder!
好きでいいよ もっと大胆に
It's okay to love me! Be more daring!
好きでいいよ もっと叫んで
It's okay to love me! Scream it louder!
好きでいいよ もっと大胆に
It's okay to love me! Be more daring!
好きでいいよ もっと叫んでっ
It's okay to love me! Scream it louder!
トゲトゲ優しさきつめの キラキラ輝け 頑張っていきます！しょい！
Prickly, with a harsh kindness, shine brightly! I'll do my best! Shoi!
ワン！
One!
びっくりしたでしょ？
You were surprised, right?
今日の私が昨日より可愛いなって
That today's me is even cuter than yesterday...
ぎゅーぎゅー ぎゅっぎゅっぎゅっぎゅっ ぎゅーしてっ
Hug hug hug hug hug hug hug me!
脳内ハニーは次のオタライフ
The honey in my brain is for my next otaku life.
冷めないように知っとかなくちゃ
I need to know so it doesn't cool down.
でもぎゅーしたら大爆発
But if we hug, it'll be a massive explosion!
死にたい死にたい死にたくない 知りたくない
I wanna die, I wanna die, I don't wanna die, I don't wanna know...
ずっと友達だね 永遠永遠永遠わからない
We'll always be friends, forever, forever, forever unknown.
だけど恋はバラバラ
But love is in pieces.
私 ち、ち、ち、ち、ち、ち、ち、ちーぎゅぅ
I'm a ch-ch-ch-ch-ch-ch-ch-chigyu!
ぎゅー！
Squeeze!
そこそこ炎上 未来永劫
Moderate backlash, forever and ever.
そこそこ大打撃 未来かっさらって
A bit of a big blow, snatching away the future.
未来ちらちら 福袋みたい
The future is flickering, like a lucky bag.
綺麗な色が見えたから
Because I saw a beautiful color,
これにしようかな
I think I'll go with this one.
ぎゅー！
Squeeze!
ぎゅー！ ぎゅー！ ぎゅー！ ぎゅー！
Hug! Hug! Hug! Hug!
お星様になっちゃう前に
Before I turn into a star,
間違っても可愛くなれるうちに
while I can still be cute even by mistake...
一番可愛い時に死にたい
I want to die when I'm at my absolute cutest.
ねえ 全然死なないね
Hey, you don't die at all, do you?
私 ち、ち、ち、ち、ち、ち、ち、ちーぎゅぅ
I'm a ch-ch-ch-ch-ch-ch-ch-chigyu!
死んでる暇ない 可愛く生きていきたい
No time to die, I want to live cutely!
そこそこ炎上 未来永劫
Moderate backlash, forever and ever.
今更どうこう 未来全部入り
Too late to do anything about it, the future is all-inclusive.
先に行ってて 今私はして
Go on ahead, right now I'm doing...
もっと凄く魅力的な女の子になろう
...I will become an even more charming girl.
「○歳になっても可愛いね」じゃないの！
"It's not 'You're cute even at XX years old'!"
こっちは努力して可愛いやってんの！
"I'm putting in actual effort to be cute!"
何十何歳経ったって可愛いの！
"No matter how many tens of years pass, I'm cute!"
ほんとそんなの当たり前だもん
"Seriously, that's just a given."
言わせないでよ、そっちから言って？
"Don't make me say it, say it from your end?"
「今日も可愛いね」でしょ？
"It's 'You're cute today too,' right?"
今日も可愛いね
"You're cute today too!"
可愛いね
"You're cute!"
可愛い！
"Cute!"
今日も可愛い
"Cuter today too!"
今日も可愛い！
私今日も可愛いね
"I'm cute today too, right?"
よし、今日も可愛いぞ！
"Alright, I'm cute today too!"
未来ちらちら おいでよおいで
"The future is flickering, come here, come here!"
私を見つけてはもっとリロードして
"Find me and reload me even more!"
未来ちらちら 怖いからこそ
"The future is flickering, precisely because it's scary."
今思っている通りに行きたい
"I want to go exactly as I'm thinking right now."
そこそこ炎上 未来永劫
"Moderate backlash, forever and ever."
そこそこ大打撃 未来かっさらって
"A bit of a big blow, snatching away the future."
未来ちらちら 福袋みたい
"The future is flickering, like a lucky bag."
綺麗な色が見えたから これにしようかな
"Because I saw a beautiful color, let's go with this one."
だってらぶ！
"Because, love!"
だってらぶ
"Because, love."
君にぽいっ 恋の SOS
"Poi to you! Love's SOS!"
ずっと胸が苦しいんです
"My chest has been hurting the whole time."
早くレスキュー 好きのテレパシーに
"Quickly, rescue! To my telepathy of love..."
早く気づいて
"...quickly realize it!"
初めて出会った日から
"Since the day we first met,"
ハートが震えてたんだよ
"my heart has been trembling, you know."
無意識に意識しちゃう
"Unconsciously, I become conscious of you."
この感じはきっと急上昇で
"This feeling is definitely rising rapidly."
求め合うだけで顔が熱いの
"Just seeking each other makes my face hot."
話しかけられて頭がパニック
"Being spoken to puts my head in a panic."
ときどき シクシク 泣いて
Sometimes weeping silently,
恋は ちっとも 叶わない
my love doesn't come true at all.
どうすれば いいの
What should I do
こんな気持ちは
with these feelings?
君との 相性診断
Our compatibility reading...
星占いなら そう グッド グッド
...says we are "so good, good" according to astrology.
友達なんかじゃ ないよ
We are definitely not just friends,
ときめいてるよ
my heart is fluttering.
君に ポラリス 恋の SOS
To you, Polaris, a love SOS.
ずっと 胸が 苦しいんです
My chest has been aching all this time.
早く レスキュー
Quickly, rescue me!
好きの テレパシー
My telepathy of love...
に早く気づいて
...please notice it quickly!
これは ポラリス 恋の SOS
This is Polaris, a love SOS.
もっと 君に 近づきたい
I want to get closer to you.
終わらせて 片想い
Put an end to this one-sided love.
マイ・ハート 全部
My heart, completely...
抱きしめて
...embrace it all!
君が 好きな 音楽や
The music you like,
映画のこと リサーチして
researching the movies...
SNS 見るたびに
Every time I check your social media,
いいね 押すの
giving a "like"...
アピールだよ
...that's my appeal to you!
一日中 君のこと
All day long, thinking of you...
考えてて 妄想しながら
...and fantasizing,
ニヤついてしまった
I ended up grinning.
明日は どんな 服
Tomorrow, what kind of clothes
着ていこうかな
should I wear?
君を 想うだけで
Just thinking of you
なんか 照れる
makes me feel a bit embarrassed.
君の名を 呼べば
If I call your name,
ただそれだけで ドリーミン ドリーミン
just that alone makes me dream, dream...
溺れそうな 私は
I feel like I'm drowning,
助け出して
so please save me!
君に ポラリス 恋の SOS
To you, Polaris, a love SOS.
ずっと 胸が 苦しいんです
My chest has been aching all this time.
早く レスキュー
Quickly, rescue me!
好きの テレパシー
My telepathy of love...
に早く気づいて
...please notice it quickly!
これは ポラリス 恋の SOS
This is Polaris, a love SOS.
もっと 君に 近づきたい
I want to get closer to you.
終わらせて 片想い
Put an end to this one-sided love.
マイ・ハート 全部
My heart, completely...
抱きしめて
...embrace it all!
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our fresh-born heartbeats resonate!
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
The best time, with the best companions!
きらめきに乗って
Ride on the sparkle!
覚えてるかな 最初の歌
Do you remember our very first song?
私 声が 震えていた
My voice was trembling back then.
あの日から続く未来は
The future continuing from that day...
みんなと掴んだ今日だよ
...is this "today" we grabbed together!
もっと もっと もっと もっと
More, more, more, more!
加速するハート
My accelerating heart!
行くよ どこまでも
Let's go, no matter how far!
準備はオッケー？
Are you ready?
ひらいて 夢の扉を
Open the door to our dreams!
重なり合った手は ぎゅっと離さずに
Let's never let go of our joined hands!
ひとりひとり 違う色 描きだす ときめき
Each and every one of us painting a different colored excitement!
振り向くことなく まっすぐに
Without looking back, straight ahead...
行くよ 夢見る空へ
...let's go, to the dreaming sky!
笑い合ったことや
The times we laughed together...
尽きそうにない話題
...and our endless conversations,
思い出いっぱいなのに あともう少しの日々
there are so many memories, yet just a little more time left together...
...想いに
...by the accelerating feelings...
戸惑いを覚えた
I felt bewildered.
ずっと追いかけた 理想の姿は
The ideal self I've always chased
まだ届かなくて遠いけど
is still out of reach and far away,
きっとこの瞬間のかけがえないみんなで
but with everyone who makes this moment irreplaceable...
共に行こうよ！
Let's go together!
手を繋いで
Hand in hand,
3・2・1
3... 2... 1...
輝き宿して
We harbor the radiance...
夢の場所へ！
...to the place of our dreams!
駆け抜けていく 僕たちの青春の光は
The light of our youth running through
誰にも止められないよ！
Cannot be stopped by anyone!
笑い合う分だけ
As much as we laugh with each other...
零れる涙さえ
...and even the spilling tears...
ほら 輝かせ
Look, we'll make them shine!
あすいろClearSky
[Song: Asuiro ClearSky]
背伸びしては 手を伸ばす憧れの
Reaching out on tiptoes to our aspiration,
行き先示す 星になろう
let's become the stars that show the way.
つまずくその度に 手を差し伸べ合えたら
Every time we stumble, if we can reach out to each other...
すぐに届くはずさ
...we'll surely reach it in no time.
そっと踏み出した 小さな勇気が
The small courage we gently stepped forward with,
もう消えないように 繋げよう
let's connect it so it will never fade away.
不安も愛しさも 大切に抱きしめて
Embracing both anxiety and tenderness dearly...
共に行くよ！
...we will go together!
目を合わせて
Locking eyes...
3・2・1
3... 2... 1...
晴れ渡る希望へ
To the clear blue hope...
飛び出せるよ！
...we can leap forward!
突き抜けていく 僕たちの透き通る決意は
Our crystal-clear determination breaking through,
まだまだ 止められないよ！
cannot be stopped just yet!
ありきたりな今日こそ
Exactly because of this ordinary today,
トキメキに変えて もっと
we'll turn it into excitement even more.
僕たちが いつまでも
As we will always...
背中を押すから！
...push you forward from behind!
Shiny Smily Story
[Song: Shiny Smily Story]
憧れの舞台 立ちたい
I want to stand on the stage of my dreams,
らしく輝きたい
I want to shine in my own way.
ときに涙して
Shedding tears at times...
また笑い合いたい
...I want to laugh together again.
同じ未来を見たい
I want to see the same future,
あの夢手（て）にしたい
I want to grasp that dream.
踏み出そう
Let's take a step forward...
奇跡の 一歩を
...on this miraculous step!
息切らして 夢追いかけたい
Out of breath, I want to chase the dream,
ワクワク止まらない
the excitement won't stop!
想像超えてく
Going beyond imagination...
世界見せてあげる
...I will show you the world!
アクセスしてみない？
Won't you try to access?
後悔なんてここにない
There are no regrets here.
それぞれ違った
With each of our different...
ココロで
...hearts...
作る world
...we create this world.
はい、ということで
All right, so...
ホロライブ、いに、ホロライブメ... ホロラ...
Holo... Hololi... Hololive mem... Hololi...
自分の事務所なのに！
Even though it's my own agency!
あ、でした。
Ah, yes, it was.
いや、どうだった？なんか、激エモだったんじゃないですか？
So, how was it? Wasn't it super emotional?
そしてね、この衣装は初めてもらったアイドル衣装なのでございますよ。
Also, this outfit is actually the very first idol costume I received.
なんか、あの時を思い出して、なんか、すごいジーンときてしまいますわね。
Remembering those days really touches my heart.
そう、まつりはね、元々その、アイドルデビューじゃなかったんですよ、ホロライブって。
Right, originally Matsuri and Hololive didn't debut as idols.
で、この衣装をもらって、よし、アイドルとして頑張るぞ、というね
And receiving this costume made me think, "All right, I'll do my best as an idol!"
気持ちを改めて思い出し、頑張っていこうかな、という気持ちでございます。
It refreshed that determination, making me want to keep working hard.
はい、そしてそして！今回も！
And! On top of that, this time too!
誕生日グッズでちゃいます！やったー！
We have birthday merchandise coming out! Yay!
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
ということで、1つずつ紹介していきます。
So, I'm going to introduce them one by one.
まずは、こちら！ドロロロロ...
First of all, this! Drumroll...
「薄すぎ！」マウスパッド、あ
"Too Flat!" Mouse Pad... Oh,
おっぱいマウスパッド！やったー！
Oppai mouse pad! Yay!
イラストは、えく先生！
The illustration is by Eku-sensei!
まつり待望のね、マウスパッドでございますよ。
It's the mouse pad that I've been waiting for!
もう、あの、ちなみに言うと、膨らみは、ないです。
By the way, just so you know, there's no bulge.
いいよね、こうやって、あの、癒すことは、ちょっと難しいんですが、
It's nice, right? Although, healing you this way is a bit difficult...
もうちょっとガチ恋な、きゅっ！みたいな、感じなのでね、
It's more of a "gachikoi" (serious love), squeezing sensation.
なので、もう、心から癒されていく、という感じで。はい、どうですか？素晴らしいグッズでございましょう？
So, you'll be healed from the bottom of your heart. Well, how is it? Isn't it a wonderful item?
そして続いてこちら！
And next is this!
じゃん！ランダムアクリルキーホルダー！
Tada! Random Acrylic Keyholder!
なんと、夏色まつり先生のね、描き下ろしでございますよ！
Surprisingly, they feature newly drawn illustrations by Natsuiro Matsuri-sensei!
ランダムアクリルキーホルダー。まつりがね、グッズのイラスト描くって、
Random Acrylic Keyholders. Matsuri drawing illustrations for merch...
なかなか無いでございますから、すごい愛情込めて描きました。
is very rare, so I drew them with lots of love.
もう、ちゅちゅちゅちゅってしながら描いたので、ぜひね、全種類コンプリートしてみてください。
I drew them while giving them kisses, so please try to collect all of them!
そして続いてこちら！
And next is this!
まつりちゃんのぬいぐるみ、サブカルジャージ衣装バージョンでございます！
Matsuri-chan plushie, sub-culture jersey outfit version!
えー、キービジュのね、イラストと同じサブカルジャージの衣装のなんと！ぬいが登場しちゃいますよ！
And look! A plushie of me in the same sub-culture jersey outfit as the key visual is coming out!
キービジュのように、お仕置きすることはちょっと現実だと叶わないけど、ぬいなら、ぬいなら出来ちゃう！
You can't really punish me in real life like in the key visual, but with a plushie... you can!
ということで、ぜひね、たくさん可愛がって、いろんなところに連れて行ってあげてください。
So, please shower her with love and take her to many places!
さらに！こちら！
Furthermore! This!
まつりすマグカップ！
Matsurisu Mug Cup!
みんなにはマグカップになってもらいました。「どんな罪を犯してこんな姿になっちまったんだ！」って感じでございますが、
I had everyone turn into a mug. It's like, "What sin did I commit to end up like this?!"
ま、自分なのでね、あの、「これが俺の姿か」と思いながら、使っていただけたらなと思います。まつりちゃんも使わせていただきます。
But, well, since it's you, I hope you'll use it thinking, "So this is my form." I'll use it too.
最後に
Lastly...
ボイス！じゃじゃーん！
Voice pack! Tada!
シチュエーションボイス「逆襲のマツリス」なんだ「逆襲のマツリス」ってなんだ？
Situation Voice: "The Retaliation of Matsurisu." What on earth is "The Retaliation of Matsurisu"?
はい、今回ね、キービジュのシチュエーションに至るまでのストーリーがここに
Yes, the story leading up to the situation in the key visual...
詰まっちゃってますので、どんなシチュエーションなのかちょっと気になる方はぜひゲットしてみてください。
is packed inside, so if you're curious about the situation, please get it!
そして！
And!
フルセットを購入いただいた方全員に直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードがついてきちゃいます！
Everyone who purchases the full set will get a postcard with a handwritten signature and a foil-stamped printed message!
えー、ちょっとね、来年は直筆やるかちょっとまだ未定でございますので、
Well, it's still undecided if I'll do handwritten signatures next year...
ぜひね、ぜひぜひぜひぜひ、全員に書かせていただきますので、初めてなんですよそれも。
so please, please, please. I'll write them for everyone. Actually, this is a first for me.
全員にサイン書くの初めてだから、ぜひ手に入れてください。来年やるかわかんないからね。
Writing signatures for everyone is a first, so please grab one. Since I might not do it next year.
さらにですね、
Furthermore...
タレントプレミアムグッズのフルセット特典として、2024年9月から発売されたホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームで使用できるカードが1枚ついてきちゃいますよ！
as a full set bonus for the talent premium goods, you will get one card that can be used in the Hololive Official Card Game, which was released in September 2024!
まつりはね、前回のグッズでちょっと特典に付いてなかったので、今回付いてくるよって感じになっております。
My previous merch didn't have this bonus, but it will be included this time.
えー、同封する、同封であってる？日本語。
Umm, "included"... is that the right Japanese?
はい、ホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップで購入されたお客様のののの、
Yes, "For customers who purchased from the Hololive Production Official Shop..."
お客様のみの対象となっておりますので、よろしくお願いします。
It's only eligible for those customers, so thank you.
特典につくのは、ゲームで1枚だけ使用でき、推しをアピールできるキーカード、推しホロメンカードでございます。
The bonus card is an "Oshi Holomem Card"—a key card that lets you show off your favorite member, with only one allowed per game.
そしてそしてそして、さらにでございますよ、まだある、
And, and, and, there's even more, we're not done yet!
ある！アルバム！
Yes! An album!
なんとまつりちゃん、ファーストアルバム「Chasing the Dream ～スポットライトは放課後に～」がなんと、
Unbelievingly, Matsuri-chan's 1st album, "Chasing the Dream ~Spotlight is After School~"...
本日、11月1日受注開始でございます！パンパカパーン！
is starting pre-orders today, November 1st! Ta-da!
まつりちゃん初のオリジナル楽曲「君と眺める夏の花」をはじめ、これまでに配信リリースしてきた作品のほか、
Starting with Matsuri-chan's very first original song, "Kimi to Nagameru Natsu no Hana," along with previously released digital tracks,
じんさんをはじめ、豪華作曲陣が書き下ろしてくださった新規楽曲も収録しちゃってますよ！
new songs written by Jin-san and other amazing composers are also included!
計14曲の超ボリューミーなアルバムになっているので、ぜひ手に入れちゃってください！
With a total of 14 songs, it's a super-packed album, so please make sure to get it!
コンセプトはね、アイドルのまつりちゃんと、普段の女子高生のまつりちゃんの両面みたいな、両方が楽しめるようなアルバムになってます。
The concept is to showcase both sides of me—the idol Matsuri-chan and the everyday high schooler Matsuri-chan—making it an album where you can enjoy both.
形態は2つありまして、完全生産限定盤と通常盤をご用意しております。
There are two editions available: the Limited Edition and the Regular Edition.
完全生産限定盤はですね、セパレートタイプのオリジナルカレンダーがついてきちゃいますよ。
The Limited Edition comes with a separate-type original calendar.
そして両形態に封入特典として、まつりちゃんからの複製お手紙が入っています。
And as an inclusion bonus for both editions, a replica letter from Matsuri-chan is inside.
ただし、数量限定のランダムでですね、複製お手紙の代わりに直筆お手紙がもらえちゃう案内が封入されていますので、ぜひぜひゲットしちゃってください。
However, in a limited, random selection, a voucher to get a handwritten letter instead of a replica is included, so please grab one!
以上、アルバム情報でした！
That's all for the album information!
そしてなんと！
And guess what!
アルバムに収録する新曲のうち1曲をですね、
One of the new tracks on my upcoming album...
本日この後披露しちゃいます！
...will be performed right here, right now today!
タイトルは、
The title is...
「ウーニャカ」にゃにゃにゃー！
\"Woo-Nyaka\"! Nyan-nyan-nyan!
作曲はですね、かいりきベアさんに作曲いただきました！
It was composed by the amazing Kairiki Bear!
めちゃめちゃ可愛い！
It is incredibly cute!
MVもですね、この後プレミア公開ありますので、
The MV will also have a YouTube Premiere after this,
えー、0時から、あの、楽曲リリースもありますので、
and the song will be officially released at midnight,
あの、ぜひよろしくお願いしますね。
so please look forward to it!
プ、プレミア、プレミア公開も一緒に見ようね！
Let's watch the premiere together, okay?
はい！
Yes!
じゃあちょっと着替えてきますので、
Alright, I'm going to go change my outfit,
ちょっとここで待ってて。
so please wait here for a bit.
ワクワクって言いながらね、あのゲストパートと同じように、
Keep saying \"waku-waku\" (excited) just like during the guest part...
ワクワクって言いながら待ってて。
...and wait for me while being all excited!
じゃあ行ってきます！
Okay, I'm off!
ワクワク…
Waku-waku...
真夜中にトケタ感情は爪立てて
My emotions, dissolved in the dead of night, claw their way out...
檻から見慣れた世界は牙向いて
and the familiar world bares its fangs from this cage.
真夜中見かねた感情は飢えた目で
Unable to bear the dead of night, my emotions look with hungry eyes,
軽やかに逃げた優しさ求めて
gracefully fleeing, searching for kindness.
「愛されたい」の想い 愛されないの Give me
\"I want to be loved,\" is my wish. You won't love me? Give it to me!
「愛してる」も重い？ 愛さえ無いの？ もういい？
Is \"I love you\" too heavy? Is there no love at all? Are we done?
愛情結晶頂戴 あなたを見てるのにゃ保存
Give me the crystallization of your love! I'm looking right at you, nya!
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おねだり
Nyan-nyaka ring-ring-ring, begging you...
さあ手懐けてよ もっと めいいっぱい
Come on, tame me as much as you possibly can!
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おでかけ？
Nyan-nyaka ring-ring-ring, going out?
しがみついて何処も行かせない！
I'll cling to you and won't let you go anywhere!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン 甘いキャンディ頂戴な
Woo-nyaka nyan-nya woo-nyan-nyan, give me sweet candy!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン ハッピーライフ頂戴な保存
Woo-nyaka nyan-nya woo-nyan-nyan, give me a happy life!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン 叱らないで頂戴な
Woo-nyaka nyan-nya woo-nyan-nyan, please don't scold me!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン ほんとの「好き」頂戴な
Woo-nyaka nyan-nya woo-nyan-nyan, give me your true \"love\"!
縄張り土足で感情目丸くして
Treading into my territory, my emotional eyes widen,
幸せになれた未来が牙向いて
and a future where we could've been happy bares its fangs.
突き放さないでいて切り捨てず傍で
Don't push me away, don't cast me aside, stay by my side...
お傍で お傍で 見ているのにゃ
...by my side, by my side, watching over you, nya!
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おねがい
Nyan-nyaka ring-ring-ring, please...
さあ頭撫でて もっと ぜーいっぱい
Come on, pet my head with all your might!
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おあずけ？
Nyan-nyaka ring-ring-ring, putting it on hold?
甘えて泣いて此処に居させて！保存
Let me cry, let me be spoiled, let me stay here!
ニャンニャカ言ったって伝わんない？
Even if I say \"nyan-nyaka,\" doesn't it reach you?
どーしたってこーしたって寂しいの
No matter what I do, I'm just so lonely!
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おもいっきり
Nyan-nyaka ring-ring-ring, with all my heart...
あざとい声 わざと聞かせる
I'll let you hear my cute voice on purpose!
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おねだり
Nyan-nyaka ring-ring-ring, begging you...
さあ手懐けてよ もっと メーいっぱい
Come on, tame me as much as you possibly can!
ニャンニャカ リンリンリン おやすみ？
Nyan-nyaka ring-ring-ring, time for bed?
しがみついて今夜寝かせない！
I'll cling to you and won't let you sleep tonight!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン 甘いキャンディ頂戴な
Woo-nyaka nyan-nya woo-nyan-nyan, give me sweet candy!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン ハッピーライフ頂戴な
Woo-nyaka nyan-nya woo-nyan-nyan, give me a happy life!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン 抱きしめて頂戴な
Woo-nyaka nyan-nya woo-nyan-nyan, please hold me tight!
ウーニャカ ニャンニャ ウーニャンニャン ほんとの「好き」頂戴な
Woo-nyaka nyan-nya woo-nyan-nyan, give me your true \"love\"!